Guide to the Charles McKinley Papers 1930-1968
Special Collections and University Archives, University of Oregon Libraries
- President’s Water Resources Policy Commission, 1950; 0.5 linear feet (Box 16)
  Major documents include the “Stanford University Group response to request from the President’s Water Resources Policy Commission,” (May 1950), and the Pacific Northwest Field Committee, “The Columbia River basin, waster resources development principles and policy problems (May 1950). McKinley’s report is titled, “Regional development and stabilization,” (September 1950).
  The Commission issued a three-volume Report (U. S. Government Printing Office, 1950-51).
- Princeton University, 1950; 2.0 folders (Box 16)
  Study of the field services of the U. S. Department of the Interior.
  Correspondence, and studies, 1950. In 1950 Princeton University, through its Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affiars, was under contract with the Department of the Interior to make a survey of field services of that department. Mr. McKinley was consultant for the study.
  Files include administrative correspondence, and copies of seven undated studies:
  1) The Bonneville Administration
  2) The Bureau of Land Management
  3) The Bureau of Reclamation
  4) The Field Committees
  5) The Fish and Wildlife Service
  6) The Geological Survey
  7) National Park Service
  There is also a consolidated “Report on the field services of the Department of the Interior, September 15, 1950, “prepared by the members of the faculty and staff of Princeton University (mimeographed, 33 p.).
- Social Science Research Council, 1939-1940; 2.0 linear feet (Box 16-17)
  Public administration and the United States Department of Agriculture, 1939-1940.
  Notes on Department of Agriculture operations in Oregon. Mostly a series of interviews with USDA personnel in Oregon concerning their work, the duties and responsibilities of their office, and often with statements about the history of agencies and activities. Includes data on forestry, soil conservation, range management, game management, recreation, the operation of the Agricultural Adjustment Administration, and experiment stations.
  This data was gathered for John M. Gaus, whose book, Public Administration and the United States Department of Agriculture, was published by the Committee on Public Administration of the Social Science Research and a memorandum, “Administration of the AAA in Oregon,” based on notes, and dealing “solely with the conservation side of the Agricultural Adjustment Administration” (n. d.). There is also a “Memorandum for John Gaus concerning the regional pattern for the Forest Service in Region Six.” (n. d.)
- Valley Authorities, 1945-1950; 3.0 linear feet (Box 17-19)
  File of correspondence, documents and related material concerning valley authorities, 1945-1950. Includes Missouri Valley Authority, and the proposed Columbia Valley Authority. One folder deals with the Northwest Development Association. This file was used for Mr. McKinley’s book, Uncle Sam in the Pacific Northwest (Berkeley, 1952), and as source material for various papers, addresses and reports.
  With this file are two and one half feet of carded notes and interviews on valley authorities and related problems.
- War Production Board, 1942; 1.0 folder (Box 19)
  Working papers of assistant to administrative office, 1942.
  Memoranda, interviews, proposals.
  In 1942 the War Production Board needed to establish field offices and devise field manuals for industry branches, and to develop an administrative plan for issuance for priority orders. Mr. McKinley, as a “Procedural consultant,” assisted in the planning and execution of both these requirements.
- Personal papers
  - Correspondence, 1945-1968
    - General, 1.0 folder (Box 19)
    - American Political Science Association, 1.0 folder (Box 19)
  - Book: Management of Land and Related Water Resources in Oregon, 1.0 folder (Box 19)
  - Resources for the Future, 2.0 folders (Box 19)
  - Sawyer, Robert, 1.0 folder (Box 19)
  - Book: Uncle Sam in the Pacific Northwest, 1.0 folder (Box 19)
  - Other
    - Reed College material (outlines, syllabi, etc.) (Box 19)
    - Student papers, McKinley, at Washington and Wisconsin (Box 19)
    - Manuscripts (Box 19)
    - Published pieces, including printed and mimeographed (Box 19)